Andrew Reed

Trewidland, Cornwall, UK - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Andrew-Reed/4144a2207b1df1ba

Principal engineer experienced in electronic system and low level design (analog and digital hardware, firmware, micro-controllers, and software development). Product development, technical sales, business management, team management and coaching, education and training.

IT, computing, electronics design and engineering, UNIX, C++ and assembler.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Science and Engineering Teacher

Tavistock Community College - Tavistock - July 2016 to Present

NQT teaching KS3 science, KS4 physics and KS5 electronic engineering.

Initial teacher training in science

Peninsula SCITT - St Austell, UK - 2015 to 2016

with a physics specialism.

Principal Engineer

CleverSMART - Sheffield - August 2006 to August 2015

Using business management, marketing and electronic engineeringl skills, built and branded a car electronics installation and innovative car body and alloy wheel repair business.

Business Manager

British Telecom plc - Leeds - April 1991 to August 2006

Technical Engineering Sales, Computer network design Engineering, Sales team management

Business Manager Technical Sales-engineering team

British Telecom plc - 2002 to 2006

Promoted to Business Manager with responsibility for managing a technical sales team into the retail, hospitality, distribution and property services vertical market sectors.

Providing specialist support to Sales Account teams and marketing colleagues in targeted campaigns to sell converged business solutions for the corporate market. Supplying technical expertise and experience to help position BT as the prime choice for FTSE 100 and global customers.

Sales Manager IP Data and Convergence Solutions

British Telecom plc - 1997 to 2002

Promoted to sales manager to build and manage a team of data and mobility solution specialists to support account teams in selling, education and proposition development of data and mobility solutions.

Principal Role To provide specialist skills in the selling of BT data and mobility solutions to corporate accounts in the vertical markets for this diverse sector.

To manage my team following the guidelines of Investors in People (IIP) and BT Human Resource Management procedures.

To help educate the account teams in order to aid the recognition, prospecting and qualification of potential opportunities.

Specialist Sales Data

British Telecom plc - 1993 to 1997

Developed and sold UK and global wide area networking solutions for, United Transport, Compass Group and other customers in this Sector.

Received the Syncordia Specialist of the year award for the first BT sale of a combined ISDN Advantage and Managed Frame Relay solution to Compass Group.

Specialist Sales Data

British Telecom plc - 1991 to 1993

Pre-Sales technical specialist in all aspects of computer networking:

LANs - Hubs, Bridge/Routers, cabling;

WANs - ISDN, SMDS, Frame Relay and Private Circuits.

MNS - Managed Routers, ISDN, SMDS, Frame Relay.

Customer presentations, Cost Justification and ROI Workshops.

Managed and developed data strategies allowing Branch/Head Office Enterprise LAN communication for Thomas Cook and National Australia Group (Clydesdale Bank, Yorkshire Bank and NAB). Worked with HSBC, Barclays Bank, Thorn and NAG to further develop their core data and IT infrastructures for both head office and branch networking.

Account Executive/Principal Engineer

British Telecom plc - Leeds, UK - 1991 to 1991

Presentations, customer training and technical sales.

Design and development of FDDI/Ethernet multiport switch/router. Project Leader on a MiniHUB development.

Sales Product Manager

Beale International Technology Limited - 1988 to 1990

Promoted to take charge of the LAN sales group.

Responsible for marketing and direct selling of networking products and fibre optic instruments.

Product Manager for fibre optic IBM 802.5 token ring repeaters.

Planning and operating the BIT stands for trade shows and exhibi tions.

Involved in all aspects of a high technology business.

Principal engineer and team leader

Beale International Technology Limited - 1985 to 1990

Company started following a management buy out with BIT holding the rights to, and a demonstration prototype for a fibre optic local area network system. The initial team was: the Managing Director the Chairman and myself. We grew the business to 35 people and £2.5M turnover before it went into liquidation in 1990.

Principal Engineer

Beale International Technology Limited - 1985 to 1988

Head hunted from Dowty.

Developed to production the High Integrity Local Area Network (HILAN).

Succeeded in attracting £500k venture capital, £125k DTI innovation grant and £2.5m contract to complete the development and produce a HILAN system for use in the Trident Submarine, Command and Control System, with Dowty Maritime Systems.

Involved in hardware/software design and sales.

Senior Engineer

Dowty Electronics Limited Controls Division - 1983 to 1985

Experience in system and board level design of digital engine control systems.

Designed a semi-custom integrated circuit (LSI Logic 4200 gates) for use in a computer networking interface conforming to the military standard 1553B.

Successfully completed within rigid time constraints, a number of electronic system designs for use with the in-house backplane/bus. These have now been used in a number of military vehicle and aeronautical engine control systems.

Management Trainee/Sponsored Student at University

British Steel Corporation - 1978 to 1982

Management training program.

EDUCATION

BSc. in Physics

Dip.Tech Integrated Circuit System Design

Teach in Secondary Schools

SKILLS

High Speed Digital Design (10+ years), Firmware design C, C++, Assembler (10+ years)